André de Paula Terceiro

Brazilian, divorcied, 42 years

Address: Rua Pedro de Toledo, 209 - house 4 - Jardim Beval - Barueri - São Paulo - SP

Note: I can work in São Paulo and anothers cities

Telephone: (11) 98289-9112

E-mail: andreterceiro@yahoo.com.br, andrerapt82@gmail.com, andre@terceiro.com.br

Curriculum summary:

Data processing technician since 12/2001. I've been working with web programming since 2003, for example with Ruby, PHP, ASP, Actionscript (Flash), .NET (Visual Basic and a little bit of C#). Groovy and Javascript (including Node.JS) and Arduino. I use object orientation, MVC (mainly CakePHP, Code Igniter and Zend Framework, but I've studied others like Symfony), Ajax (via Xajax or directly with Jquery), visual effects with Jquery etc. I use template engines (various, depending on technology). In Flash I currently program AS3, integrating with PHP via XML or AMFPHP, but I've already programmed in AS2. The main types of systems I've developed are websites, administrative systems, various reports, e-commerce and

touchscreen multimedia for events (involving integration with external hardware, face detection via camera etc). I've also worked with Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, Helm, Azure Pipelines, AWS Cloudformation, Rancher and other technologies. In terms of cloud products, I have worked, for example, with pipelines on Azure, artifact repositories and Git repositories on Azure, boards on Azure, ACR, AKS, lambda functions on AWS, Dynamo DB, EKS, etc. PHP Brazil Moderator on Facebook until Facebook blocked my account without giving me a chance to try to explain myself. I made another account...

Goal:

Programming / systems analysis

Formation::

- Post Graduation in Software Engineering São Judas Tadeu University Completed in 07/2013
- Technologist in Precision Mechanics (Mechatronics/Robotics) FATEC. Completed in 07/2007
- Computer Technician (former data processing technician course) ETE Camargo Aranha. Completed on 12/2001
- Electronics technician ETE José Rocha Mendes. Completed on 07/2001

Certifications:

- CCNA Cisco (2002-2005)
- CCAI Cisco (Netacademy CCNA instructor)

Complementary courses and congresses:

- Various Meetups
- Arduino with Blender: MIS. Completed in 08/2009
- PHP Conference 2006 and 2012
- Linux IBTA systems and network administration. Completed on 11/2003
- Cisco Networking Academy. Completed in 2001
- Installation and maintenance of computers Senai. Completed on 06/1999

Professional experience

Fixed-term projects: May 2022 (current)

Role: Senior devops programmer or N1 support

During this period when I was not employed as a CLT, I chose to work as a PJ/cooperative or on personal projects;

- For WABiz I programmed a bot for WhatsApp and a skill for Alexa. Wabiz was an exception as I spent a CLT period there. I have a letter of recommendation from WABiz (https://www.terceiro.com.br/carta-recomendacao-wabiz.pdf)
- Senior devops programmer allocated to Assaí by Decision: At Assaí I learned how to work with some "Low Code" platforms: Digibee and Automation Anywhere.

I also created a system in Node.JS that integrated with DynamoDB and SQS. I used it in this system uses TypeScript, Jest for testing (in addition to the collections exported from Postman that ended up being used for testing as well), the AWS SDK to integrate with AWS, I documented it with Swagger, I created very rich documentation in README.md etc. On the way I tried to achieve the objectives, I even used my personal Amazon account for testing. In addition to the Postman collections I made, Jest ones were used for unit testing, including tests involving requests with Supertest.

- Self-employed: I did freelance work and resolved personal things during this period
- Devops programmer through Decision (another client): I worked allocated by Decision to a client (which they preferred that I not reveal). Most of the time I worked with Jenkins pipelines, there was no time to stay until they migrated everything to Gitlab. Depending on what I had to insert, if the information was in a repository, I would parse it in PHP. It was a cool place to work. I'm not going to add any media because I felt it wasn't cool to disclose some information. Note: I was not fired, I chose to leave there to work on another project.
- N1 support for CERC through Rhodio: it was a cool experience. CERC is a registrar, I learned a little there about the role of registrars, financiers, payment arrangements, the role of 7COM's central information base. In addition to answering calls, I generated some praised documentation there.

Riachuelo: from 06/2020 to 02/2022 Role: Senior devops programmer

<u>Example of activities</u>: I am a happy member of Riachuelo's center of technological excellence. There my role is to provide tools for the development teams to work with. I've worked for example with Lambda AWS, Jenkins, Node.JS and the programming languages Groovy and Javascript.

Self-employed while not in a company: from 04/2020 to 06/2020

Role: Senior programmer

Examples of activities: web freelances, tutorial recording, various software development

Swide: from 03/2020 to 04/2020 Role: Senior programmer

Examples of activities: I basically worked in an online bingo team.

I faced a new challenge at Swide. A big, ambitious, cool Project.. I did a lot of things, for example 14 branches in 7 days, counting the time to learn the company's own framework.

I was hired for a project. Unfortunately the customer wanted to abort. I left with a feeling of accomplishment. That's why the time is short.

It was a nice experience.

Fundação Cásper Libero: from 03/2014 to 02/2020

Role: Senior programmer

<u>Examples of activities</u>: There is a link to my LinkedIN at http://www.terceiro.com.br. See there please.

For professional growth, I faced a new challenge. In FCL programming was in PHP (using Wordpress, Zend Framework, Symfony and Laravel for example), Ruby, Phyton, Node (Javascript), Java and applications with Cordova. We took care of Gazeta Esportiva, Gazeta FM and AM, TV Gazeta and São Silvestre.

Promo Sapiens: from 07/2008 to 03/2014

Role: Systems Analyst.

Examples of activities: There is a link to my LinkedIN profile at http://www.terceiro.com.br. See

there please.

Below is a description of some works: e-commerce All Sell (http://www.allsell.com.br), multimedia for Samsung, Avon, Telefônica and Ideal Invest (more than 20, using Arduino, Visual Basic, Flash, PHP, touchscreens, face detection via camera, barcode detection, data registration, activation of fluorescent lamps via Flash, multimedia synchronization on different PCs via network, etc.), Lig Lig website (old, administrative system in PHP, display data, AJAX, effects with Jquery etc), Hotma (old, http://www.hotma.com.br, administrative system in PHP, integration with Flash), system for generating email marketing for Ação Informática (system PHP administrative and HTML generation for triggering), administrative system and Flash integration for Promo Sapiens website (old), virtual poll and reports for Samsung, system for generating email signatures and inserting into email programs (Outlook, Thunderbird, Macintosh Mail etc) for di verses clients (formerly we used http://www.ff.rec.br/sim/assinatura_email/), interaction with sensors and LEDs for Telefônica (impact measurement via accelerometer and activation of LEDs through a microcontroller – Arduino's Atmega 168), Some things in Girafa's website (in "tableless" with Jquery) (http://www.girafa.com.br)

Grito Ateliê Digital: from 10/2007 to 04/2008

Role: Web programmer

<u>Examples of activities</u>: There is a link to my LinkedIN profile at http://www.terceiro.com.br. See there please.

Description of some works: website http://www.sabrinamatar.com.br/ - old version (modules for administrative system and front-end), Editora C4 website (http://www.editorac4.com.br) system administrative, data presentation, photo slide show), extensive research form for Sesi / Ação Educativa in 2008, e-mail marketing tool customization (formerly 2Send – the agency unfortunately is closed), tool customization for project management (Rolim Consult), administrative system and showcase for the Casa das Construções website (http://www.casadasconstrucoes.com.br/ - I don't know why they changed the website), various contributions to the website Conceiro Brazil (http://www.conceitobrazil.com.br/).

<u>Self-employed</u>: from 01/2005 to 09/2007 as main activity; since 10/2007 as a complementary activity

Role: web programming (PHP), maintenance of networks, servers and PABX; Examples of activities: There is a link to my LinkedIN at http://www.terceiro.com.br. See there please.

The description of some works follows: reports for the Anuncio Certo site (old version of the site – the company closed), participation in the Names 2 Glue site (http://www.names2glue.com.br – the site was in Flash previously and not now,and I made the e-commerceof the website), changes on the Atrasorb website (http://www.atrasorb.com.br). For Torresan Eventos: administrative system and reports for registration of receptionists, forms and reports for research carried out in events, equipment maintenance, network and internal server.

TXT Marcom: from 06/01/2003 to 15/06/2004

<u>Role</u>: Web programming (PHP), maintenance of servers, network and PABX and internal support <u>Examples of activities</u>: There is a link to my LinkedIN at http://www.terceiro.com.br. See there please.

Description of some jobs: registration system for events and printing of identification cards on thermal printers, generation of various reports, internal systems, maintenance on Linux and Windows servers and internal support for users.

FASTDATA Informática LTDA: from 06/06/2002 to 12/15/2002

Role: Cisco Netacademy Instructor

Activity: Official Cisco Systems training (Cisco Networking Academy), preparatory to CCNA certification.

<u>Cisco Systems (outsourced)</u>: from 02/15/2002 to 06/01/2002 <u>Role</u>: Customer service (Help desk)

Languages

Constant reading of various technical documents in English, intermediate in conversation in this language. I'm in Duolingo's diamond division.